[

**OsmAnd**](https://osmand.net/)[Docs](https://osmand.net/docs/intro)[Blog](https://osmand.net/blog)[💳 Purchases](https://osmand.net/docs/user/purchases)[🌍 Map](https://osmand.net/map)[🚵‍♂️ Join us](https://osmand.net/docs/hiring)

1\. Who we are[​](#1-who-we-are "Direct link to 1. Who we are")
---------------------------------------------------------------

**1.1.** We are OsmAnd B.V. located at Logger 41, 1186 RM, Amstelveen, the Netherlands.  
**1.2.** OsmAnd B.V. ("Company") and its subsidiaries recognize the importance of the user privacy and protection of personal data.

2\. This Privacy Policy[​](#2-this-privacy-policy "Direct link to 2. This Privacy Policy")
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**2.1** This Privacy Policy describes the way the Company collects and processes the information provided by the end users, including personalized or non-personalized types of data. Personalized data is understood as the information may include the data that identifies or describes a user or another identifiable individual. Non-personalized data is the information that does not identify any user, in particular, providing anonymous, generalized information.

**2.2** The Company is committed to the principles of personal data security and only uses the information to provide better service to the users.

3\. The information Company collects[​](#3-the-information-company-collects "Direct link to 3. The information Company collects")
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**3.1** Company aggregates non-personal data which cannot identify a user. Such data includes the apps' installs, the frequency of the launches, the devices' models, software versions, the countries where the application is used, the language and downloaded maps info. Also, the users may be asked to leave an email to get access to certain additional features and to participate in marketing activities and provide non-personalized data about the use of different screens in the application without any user input data to let Company improve certain functionality.

**3.1.1** Info about downloaded maps helps to learn the region popularity to provide the best service where it is most used. It's important to provide maps as fast as possible for users who just installed the app or need them urgently, in contrast of regular batch updates.

* The map download data is tied to the [UUID (Unique User Identifier)](https://osmand.net/docs/legal/terms-of-use#6-unique-user-indentifier) and contains the IP adress which was used to download maps, the date and time when it was downloaded, the list of downloaded regions.
* OsmAnd doesn’t collect any data if map was installed manually.

**3.1.2** Info about opened screens is disabled by default. By enabling it you are sharing:

* List of names of used screens (features) without any user content / user input data. For example, you share you used the search feature, but never share what you were searching for.
* Screens data is tied to the UUID (Unique User Identifier).

**3.1.3** You always can control what data to share in [the General settings](https://osmand.net/docs/user/personal/global-settings#privacy-and-security) of OsmAnd app.

**3.2** Collected data may be used for reports and statistics as well as while the OsmAnd discount pop-up notifications, according to this Privacy Policy. Collected data never shared with third party.

**3.3** We strongly believe in the principle of data protection and safety, thus, the Company does not collect, store, process or transfer any personal information of users besides the cases when such information is provided by the users with their clear consent.

**3.4** The Company may disclose the information provided by the users or collected otherwise in certain exceptional cases including a legal process or by request of the law enforcement agencies. It is also possible in case of investigations, including those concerning possible fraud, terms of use infringement or other cases that are potentially harmful to the Company. Besides that, data can be shared or disclosed to prevent harm or damage to the users.

**3.5** If Company faces reformation such as acquisition by another business, company merger, or other, the information collected by the Company can be transferred to the according parties.

**3.6** Certain parts of non-personalized data can be shared with the partners of the Company in the amounts, necessary to ensure cooperation between the Company and its partners or service providers.

4\. OsmAnd Tracker plugin[​](#4-osmand-tracker-plugin "Direct link to 4. OsmAnd Tracker plugin")
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**4.1** You provide your mobile number to us for identify Telegram Account. We do not collect your mobile number, the Company only transfer this to Telegram ([Privacy Policy of Telegram](https://telegram.org/privacy)) with your agreement. The Company follows Privacy Policy and uses Telegram Library to send messages which follows [Telegram Privacy Policy](https://telegram.org/privacy). The Company will store your location information for up to 48 hours in order to provide a stable data buffer. (These data will be protected and not shared with third parties).

5\. OsmAnd Cloud[​](#5-osmand-cloud "Direct link to 5. OsmAnd Cloud")
---------------------------------------------------------------------

**5.1** OsmAnd Cloud is the feature of backup and synchronization of your data. To work with OsmAnd Cloud (OsmAnd Pro subscribers), you provide us with access to your email to identify your account. Your email and identification token are stored on the physical OsmAnd server. On the cloud servers [Scalwey](https://images-www.scaleway.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/16075241/EN-Privacy-Policy-2020.pdf) and [Amazon](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) we store the data necessary for the application's synchronization function to work, including identification token, gpx tracks, maps, settings, video and audio notes, favorites, and other what you want to synchronize. When you use the delete your data function, your data will be permanently deleted from physical and cloud servers within a week. All these data will be protected and not shared with third parties.

**5.2** Users always can delete their accounts via [direct link](https://osmand.net/map/delete-account). The user's OsmAnd Cloud data will be deleted at once after the account is deleted.

6\. Changes to this Policy[​](#6-changes-to-this-policy "Direct link to 6. Changes to this Policy")
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**6.1** This Policy can be updated anytime at the discretion of the Company. By using the Company’s products, the users agree to fully comply with the Policy and understand that their data can be processed under the rules mentioned here.

**6.2** If this Privacy Policy changes in any way, we will post an updated version on this page. We recommend you regularly review this page to ensure that you are always aware of our information practices and any changes to such.

7\. Contact Us[​](#7-contact-us "Direct link to 7. Contact Us")
---------------------------------------------------------------

**7.1** In case of any issues or concerns related to this Privacy Policy or its fulfillment, please contact us at [contactus@osmand.net.](mailto:contactus@osmand.net.) So we can deal with your enquiry effectively, please quote this Privacy Policy. We will aim to respond to you within 30 days from receipt of request.

**Last updated: December 11, 2023**

OsmAnd

Community

Telegram chat

More

Copyright © 2024 OsmAnd BV.
